{
  "meta": {
    "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
    "perDifficulty": 20,
    "createdAt": "2026-01-17T09:57:32.275375"
  },
  "problems": {
    "1": [
      {
        "id": "P2411259243856446",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "3x + 2 = 5 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7351869848123113",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "3x + 17 = 47 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "10",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3522990461141895",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "4x - 18 = -18 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9808191857888494",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "4x + 9 = 9 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P0631005370322246",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "4x - 12 = 8 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2015909928367009",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "2x - 2 = 6 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "4",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9333709799503974",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "2x + 0 = -8 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-4",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4733997676768434",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "8x + 14 = 62 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "6",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3569741760353634",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "5x - 2 = -47 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1244750082443834",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "7x - 3 = -66 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7433077055196212",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "8x + 5 = 13 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4962032265370226",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "7x - 9 = 5 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2667206958021826",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "7x + 13 = 48 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4306071520034469",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "8x - 15 = -79 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-8",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1025979077821143",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "6x + 0 = -30 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4459157630996526",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "6x - 1 = -1 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3515469837719921",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "4x + 8 = 20 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9981505977730490",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "7x + 19 = -44 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6711838888936679",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "2x - 16 = -20 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8010959755621699",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "7x + 12 = 26 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      }
    ],
    "2": [
      {
        "id": "P6780888719954488",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "2x + 18 = 3x + 23 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2359953804203523",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "2x - 16 = 3x - 20 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "4",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9494671118799198",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "7x + 4 = 6x + 14 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "10",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3720133784706837",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "4x + 3 = 8x + 39 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3143854413148815",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "4x + 5 = 6x + 21 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-8",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7356748594794277",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "5x - 19 = 2x - 25 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7749644835314882",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "8x - 4 = 2x + 26 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1226374219039708",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "5x - 8 = 8x - 20 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "4",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9972624040230418",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "9x + 8 = 3x - 40 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-8",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5421713612255623",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "7x + 15 = 2x + 15 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5087557451743008",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "4x + 3 = 3x + 2 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7903730608077492",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "5x - 5 = 3x - 19 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-7",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8036617262885865",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "7x + 9 = 6x - 1 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-10",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3092907175284621",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "4x - 16 = 2x - 2 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "7",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P0737507129112390",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "8x + 16 = 7x + 21 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6801089906495810",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "3x + 9 = 8x + 9 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4326182864819748",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "4x - 12 = 3x - 11 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1619669595558996",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "3x - 10 = 5x + 8 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2506053089819990",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "7x - 15 = 5x - 21 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3028246061088760",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "6x + 20 = 3x + 50 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "10",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      }
    ],
    "3": [
      {
        "id": "P6409874272989921",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "3(x + 2) = 12 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6587328733837543",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "4(x - 4) = -4 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P0411943035217841",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "7(x + 3) = 56 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9485468539703916",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "3(x - 6) = -36 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-6",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2108083797019645",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "6(x + 4) = 60 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "6",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6389911922088705",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "8(x + 3) = 48 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9566501699544050",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "6(x + 4) = 30 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8073493144287976",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "5(x + 6) = 35 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P0729730255053457",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "6(x + 1) = 6 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4156217462141150",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "4(x + 1) = -20 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-6",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6066602628206363",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "5(x - 1) = 0 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9880233694670898",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "7(x + 5) = 28 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7606649947951748",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "8(x - 4) = -40 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2417378609364671",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "3(x - 1) = 3 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2479188825255456",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "6(x + 1) = -24 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9453848927032190",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "2(x - 2) = -14 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9626858522393368",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "8(x - 3) = 0 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7211284288221219",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "7(x + 3) = -7 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-4",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9959694110954168",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "4(x + 1) = -8 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "-3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4973702730475090",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-III-4",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "9(x - 2) = -9 를 풀어라.",
        "answer": "1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      }
    ]
  }
}